hey everyone welcome back to another
大家好，欢迎回到我的
tutorial my name is Jake and I'm going
教程。我是Jake，今天我将带
to be walking you through doing some
大家学习如何使用Production Crate中的
building explosion effects with some
一些超酷素材制作建筑物爆炸特效。废话
so without any further Ado let's go
不多说，让我们来
ahead and take a look at what we're
看看我们要
creating man this is unit 12 I'm on site
创建什么。这里是12号单元，我正在现场
prepping canisters for extermination of
准备罐子，准备消灭
Category 3 mega
3级巨型
roaches category
蟑螂。9级蟑螂，
9 copy that
收到！
[Music]
[音乐]
I love a category 9
我喜欢9级蟑螂，
pretty cool lots of fun stuff in there
非常酷，里面有很多好玩的东西，
everything from transforming CG Weaponry
从变形的CG武器
to big explosions and we'll mainly be
到大型爆炸，应有尽有。今天我们主要会
looking at today the hero building
学习
explosion effect where the rocket hits
火箭击中建筑物后，建筑物轰然倒塌的爆炸特效，
it and it all comes tumbling down and
以及
how we can combine multiple pieces of
如何将多个
stock assets together to create a
素材组合在一起，创造出
convincing effect so let's go ahead and
逼真的效果。那么，让我们马上开始吧！
Jump Right In All right so here we are
好的，我们现在
in Adobe After Effects as you can see I
在Adobe After Effects中。正如你所看到的，我
already have my footage imported so
已经导入了素材。
we're going to drag this down here to
我们将把素材拖到这里，点击
this icon to create a new composition
这个图标创建一个新的合成。
and here's our actor John stumbling back
这是我们的演员John，他踉跄后退，
and staring at the sky where the
望着天空。 这些
buildings are going to be and just from
建筑物即将出现，仅从
looking at this I know the first thing
目前的情况来看，我知道
we're going to want to do is track it
我们首先要做的是跟踪它。
considering this is a handheld movement
考虑到这是手持拍摄，
and so it does shift around just a
所以在快进/快退的过程中，画面会略微移动。在我们
before we get too far into this I want
深入讲解之前，我想
to warn you guys I am using a free
提醒大家，我使用的是
plugin from video co-pilot called FX
Video Co-Pilot 的免费插件 FX
console which allows me to hit control
Console。它允许我在
space whenever I have a layer selected
选中图层后按下 Ctrl+空格键，
and then just type in whatever I want to
然后在效果菜单中输入我想
search for in the effects menu here now
搜索的内容。
if you don't want to go grab effects
如果您不想使用 FX
console you can find the same effects
Console，也可以
that I search for here over in the
在“
effects and presets panel or just by
效果和预设”面板中找到我在这里搜索的相同效果，或者直接
coming up here to the top where the
点击顶部
effects drop down is and it has
效果下拉菜单，
everything here as well but again since
那里也包含了所有选项。不过，由于
I'm using effects console I'll just
我使用的是 FX Console，所以我
select my footage hit control space and
选择我的素材，按下 Ctrl+空格键，
then I'll type in mocha I'm going to
然后输入“mocha”。我将
select mocha AE which comes free with
选择 Mocha AE，它是
After Effects 2025 and then we'll go
After Effects 2025 自带的插件。然后，我们
ahead and click this launch mocha AE
点击“启动 Mocha AE”
button now here we are in mocha we can
按钮。现在我们已经进入了 Mocha AE，我们可以
click close go ahead and click Start the
点击“关闭”，然后点击“开始
play head is down here at the bottom and
播放”。 就在底部，
if we scrub through we're just going to
如果我们快速拖动，就要
look for a place in this footage that
找到这段素材中
has high contrast and stays in frame the
对比度高且始终在画面内的区域。
full time I think I'm going to grab the
我想我会选择
corner of this building here so let's
这个建筑物的拐角，所以我们
come up here to the X spinee tool select
来到 X 轴工具，选中
this and then we're going to draw just a
它，然后在
little box around the corner and when
拐角周围画一个小框。
you're done drawing you can right click
画完后，可以右键单击
to stop adding new points and then we're
停止添加新点。然后，我们点击
going to click this button on the left
左侧的按钮进行前
to analyze forward now once that's
向分析。
finished analyzing we can click the X in
分析完成后，点击
the top right corner and then press save
右上角的 X，然后点击保存。
now back and after effects in the
现在回到 After Effects 的效果
effects controls panel there is a drop
控制面板，有一个
down for the tracking data so we're
跟踪数据的下拉菜单，点击它，
going to click that and then click this
然后点击“
big button that says create track data
创建跟踪数据”按钮。
once you see all these key frames appear
看到所有关键帧出现后，就说明创建成功了。我们
you know it worked and we're going to
将
change the export option from cor pin to
导出选项从“角点”更改为“
transform now it's asking us where we're
变换”。现在它会询问我们
going to export this tracking data which
要将跟踪数据导出到哪里，
at the moment we don't have anything in
目前我们的合成中没有任何可以导出的目标，
our composition to export it to so what
所以
we're going to do is create a new null
我们要创建一个新的空
object by coming up to layer new null
对象。 接下来，新建一个空
object now select your footage change
对象图层。现在选择你的素材，将
the layer export to your null and then
图层导出更改为你的空对象，然后
click apply export now if you select
点击“应用导出”。如果你选中
your null zoom in here a little bit you
空对象，稍微放大一下，你
can see there's a bunch of key frames
会看到有很多关键帧，
and it sticks to the corner of that
它紧贴着建筑物的角落。
start working on our effect now that we
现在我们应该可以开始制作特效了。我们在
have this tracked here on the production
Production
crate website there's a lot of really
Crate 网站上追踪了这些素材，那里有很多
cool new building explosion assets that
很酷的建筑物爆炸素材，
we can hover over and preview and in the
我们可以将鼠标悬停在上面进行预览。在
original effect I did have this one
原始特效中，我把其中一个建筑放在
heroed in the middle cuz it explodes
中间，因为它
from the center and I wanted the rocket
从中心爆炸，我希望火箭
to hit there then I had two additional
击中那里。我还添加了两个
ones to explode to the left and then one
建筑在左侧爆炸，一个在
over to the right so grab a couple of
右侧爆炸。你可以选择几个
these whichever suit you and let's bring
你喜欢的素材，然后把
them over into after effects back and
它们导入到 After Effects 中。回到
after effects we can go to the project
After Effects，我们可以打开项目
panel and then up here in the top left
面板，然后在左上角点击“文件”&gt;“
we can go to file import file now I went
导入文件”。我已经
ahead and downloaded the three main
下载了三个主要的
building explosions that I wanted as
建筑物爆炸素材，
well as this background image which is
以及这张背景图片（
also able to be found on production
也可以在 Production Crate 上找到）。
crate so I'm going to select all four of
我将选择这四个素材，
these and hit import and just cuz I like
然后点击“导入”。 因为我喜欢
to keep my projects a little bit more
让我的项目更
organized I'm going to grab all four of
有条理一些，所以我要把这四个素材都
these and drag them into a new folder
拖到一个新文件夹里，就叫它“
and I'm just going to call this Assets
资源”吧。
Now if we bring out our hero building
现在，如果我们把主角建筑拖出来，
and place it roughly where we want it
大致放到想要的位置，稍微
maybe scale it up just a little and
放大一点，然后
scrub through our footage it's obviously
在素材里拖动，它显然会
just going to be floating there until we
漂浮在那里，直到我们
grab this Pi Whip and drag it to the
把这个 Pi Whip 拖到
null and if we scrub it through now we
空位上。现在拖动它，
can see it's sticking to the sky much
可以看到它更贴合天空了。
more but now that we've got this locked
现在我们已经把它锁定
to our footage we see the first problem
到素材上了，我们看到了需要解决的第一个问题：
is that JN and this foreground building
JN 和这个前景建筑
actually need to be in front of this
实际上需要位于
stock layer so in order to do that we're
素材图层的前面。为了做到这一点，我们需要把
going to have to chop them out from the
它们从天空中抠出来。我们会
going to use in order to get us there so
用到一些技巧来实现这一点，所以我们
layer for now select our footage and
现在先隐藏建筑图层，选择素材并
duplicate it and then let's solo the
复制一份，然后单独处理
duplicate just so we can isolate that
副本，这样我们就可以在
while we're working now just from
操作时把它隔离出来。现在，从
looking at this I can see that the sky
这个角度来看，我可以看到…… 天空明显
is definitely way brighter than the rest
比其他
of the footage so I may be able to get
素材亮得多，所以我或许可以
away with partially using the sky as a
部分地将天空用作亮度垫。
Luma mat so in order to do that I'm
为了实现这一点，我要
going to click this layer hit control
点击这个图层，按下 Ctrl+空格键
space to bring up effects console and
打开效果控制台，然后
we're going to use the colorama effect
使用 Colorama 效果。为了
now just to be tidy we can go ahead and
整洁起见，我们可以
delete mocha off of this duplic kit
删除这个复制工具包图层上的 Mocha 图层，并将输出循环的
output cycle and change the preset from
预设从“
none to ramp gray now this little wheel
无”更改为“渐变灰”。这个小旋钮可以让
just allows us to clamp specific values
我们钳制特定的数值。
so in order to do that I'm going to
为此，我要
select somewhere here in the gray area
在灰色区域内选择一个位置，
and create a new perfect white make sure
创建一个新的纯白色，确保
that this is set to 100% brightness now
亮度设置为 100%。现在，
we're going to select somewhere in here
我们再选择一个位置，
and create a new perfect black again
创建一个新的纯黑色，同样
make sure that this is set to zero and
确保亮度设置为 0，然后
click okay and you can already see what
点击确定。你已经可以看到效果了，
white outline where the sky is and a
天空部分几乎形成了纯白色轮廓，
black outline where the foreground
前景图层部分形成了黑色轮廓。
I know we're going to have to clean up
我知道有些地方需要
initially such as the choke on the hair
先清理一下，比如头发和
the jacket's too bright and we do have
夹克上的卡顿。 画面很亮，
some highlights on this building that
这栋建筑上确实有一些高光，
we're not going to be able to get rid of
我们无法用
with this effect but this is a really
这个特效完全消除，但这确实是一个
good start but rather than playing with
很好的开始。与其
these two sliders while we're staring at
盯着黑白画面摆弄这两个滑块，
it in black and white what I like to do
我更喜欢先选择
is select the stock footage that I know
我知道会放在
is going to be behind these layers and
这些图层后面的素材，
then grab the track mat pick Whip and
然后选中轨道材质选择器，
select the building explosion layer that
选择我们当前正在处理的建筑爆炸图层。
default it's using the alpha mat but I
默认情况下它使用的是 Alpha 通道材质，但我
actually want to press this button to
需要按下这个按钮将
change it to a Luma mat and then don't
其更改为亮度材质。
forget to turn the layer back on you can
别忘了重新打开图层。你可以
already see it's doing its job pretty
看到它的效果已经
well except if we zoom in here it's
很好了，只是如果我们放大来看，会发现有些
places it shouldn't be particularly the
地方确实有点显眼，特别是
jacket of our actor so what we're going
演员的外套。
to do in order to fix that is precompose
为了解决这个问题，我们需要预合成
our duplicate layer by selecting it and
复制的图层。选中它，然后按 Ctrl+
hitting control shift C and then make
Shift+C，接着点击“将
move all attributes to a new composition
所有属性移动到新合成”按钮。
and I'm going to call this skym all
我把它命名为“skym all”。好了，
right now we can go ahead and double
现在我们可以
click on this skym mat comp now here in
双击这个“skym all”材质合成了。 在
this
这个
pre-positioned to this black and white
预先定位到黑白
mat so the first thing I know we want to
背景上的素材中，我知道我们首先要
take care of is this light color on his
处理的是他夹克上的浅色，
jacket because we want this to be as
因为我们希望它
close to perfectly black as possible in
尽可能接近纯黑色，
order to block out that building so
以便遮盖住那栋建筑。
click your footage hit contrl D on the
点击素材，按键盘上的 Ctrl+D
keyboard to duplicate it go to the
复制它，然后进入
effects controls and let's delete
效果控制，删除
colorama now fortunately this character
Colorama 图层。幸运的是，这个角色
is wearing a green colored jacket so I
穿着绿色夹克，所以我
know we're going to be able to use maybe
知道我们可以使用
some sort of chroma key process in order
某种色度键技术将
to turn this into a mat to add back on
其转换为背景，然后添加
to our original which is below so let's
到下面的原始素材中。按 Ctrl+空格键
hit control space to bring up effects
打开效果
console and type in key light we're
控制台，输入 Key Light。我们
going to grab this screen Color Picker
将使用屏幕颜色选择器，选择
and grab one of the areas on his jacket
他夹克
that's pretty neutral right in the
中间比较中性的区域，
middle and then change final result to
然后将最终结果更改为
combined mat now if we change the
组合背景。现在，如果我们把
blending mode of this layer from normal
这个图层的混合模式从“正常”改为“正片叠底”，
to multiply you can see if we toggle
可以看到，如果我们切换
this on and off that we've pretty much
这个模式，
taken care of that problem we can play
这个问题基本就解决了。我们可以
with the screen gain and balance in
调整屏幕增益和平衡，
order to make this as dark as possible
使它尽可能暗，
but this is already pretty close to
但现在已经很接近了。
where we need it to be now the next
现在，我们需要把它放到合适的位置。接下来，
thing I want to do is add a black solid
我想添加一个黑色纯色图层
to cover up some of the highlights on
来遮盖这些建筑物上的一些高光。
these buildings however since this is a
但是，由于这是一个
moving shot if you remember we need that
移动镜头，如果你还记得的话，我们需要将这个
black solid to be tracked to our
黑色纯色图层跟踪到我们
original null so let's jump back over
最初的空对象上。所以，让我们回到
into our main composition click your
主合成界面，点击你的空对象，按
null hit contrl C to copy go back to to
Ctrl+C 复制，然后返回
Sky mat contrl +v to paste now let's
天空材质，按 Ctrl+V 粘贴。现在，让我们
create a new solid you can come up here
创建一个新的纯色图层。你可以点击
to layer and find new solid up here or
这里进入图层，找到“新建纯色图层”，或者
memorize that shortcut control y to
记住快捷键 Ctrl+Y 来
speed up your workflow and change this
加快你的工作流程。将图层颜色改为
to Black click okay now just to make
黑色，点击确定。现在，为了
sure it doesn't go off the edges I am
确保它不会超出边缘，我
going to scale this up a little bit and
将稍微放大它，
then parent it to our null using that Pi
然后使用之前用过的 Pi 工具将其父级化到我们的空对象上。
whip from earlier now if we temporarily
现在，如果我们暂时
hide this we can grab our mask tool and
隐藏它，就可以使用蒙版工具
zoom in to draw a rough mask around the
放大，在需要保持纯黑色的区域周围绘制一个粗略的蒙版。
perfectly black black so I'm just going
所以我要
to make sure to get the top of that
确保覆盖到
building maybe come across here I am
建筑物的顶部，也许会覆盖到这里。为了演示，我
going a little bit quick just for the
做得有点快，
sake of the tutorial but since this is
但由于它是
tracked we can get as close to the edge
跟踪的，我们可以尽可能靠近边缘。
of this building as you'd like so come
按照你想要的方式调整这个建筑，绕到
around the bottom and close off that
底部，关闭
mask and turn back on that black solid
遮罩，然后重新打开黑色纯色图层
to cover up that area and it's looking
来覆盖那个区域。
pretty good so far there's two more
目前看起来效果不错。
things I want to do in here just to
我还需要做两件事来
correct this mat the first is to get
修正这个图层。首先是去除
this pixel clouding out of the sky and
天空中的像素云，
we'll just do the same thing we did with
我们只需重复之前处理
the black solid except this time let's
黑色纯色图层的操作，只不过这次要把它
make it white so again control y on the
变成白色。再次按下键盘上的 Ctrl+Y，打开“创建纯色”工具，把它变成白色，然后
it white and click okay parent it to the
点击“确定”。将其父级设置为
null hide it grab your pen tool let's
空对象，然后隐藏它。拿起钢笔工具，在
draw a little shape around the area we
我们需要完全纯白的区域周围画一个小形状。
want perfectly white close off that mask
关闭遮罩，
and turn back on that layer now the last
然后重新打开该图层。现在，
thing I want to do in this composition
我想在这个合成中做的最后一件事
is soften these leaves since these are
是柔化这些叶子，因为它们被
crunched so hard with the colorama
Colorama 效果处理得太厉害了，
effect anything we put behind them is
任何放在它们后面的东西
going to look a little too sharp and we
看起来都会太锐利，我们
want a little bit of gray value in these
需要在这些叶子中添加一些灰色调。
leaves so in order to do that what I'm
为了实现这一点，我
actually going to do is grab this bottom
实际上要做的是选中底部
footage layer with colorama on it
带有 Colorama 效果的素材图层，
duplicate it and let's solo it for now
复制它，然后暂时将其单独显示。
open back up the output cycle so we can
重新打开输出循环，这样我们就可以
see this wheel and let's play with this
看到这个轮子了。 我们来
a little bit to soften back out that
稍微调整一下，让这
tree that's looking pretty good since
棵树看起来柔和一些。现在
we're getting all these small leaves
这些小叶子都长出来了，效果很不错。
coming back in now we don't want this
我们不想让它
affecting the whole Sky just this
影响整个天空，只想影响
section where the tree is at but if we
树所在的这部分。但如果我们
tried to mask it we'd have a couple
尝试用遮罩，会遇到几个
different problems the first of which is
问题。首先，
that regardless of if we feather this
无论我们是否羽化这个
mask or not the colorama effect is
遮罩，Colorama 效果都会
crunching that mask and it's not giving
压缩遮罩，导致羽化效果不好。
us a good feather so we're not going to
所以我们不会
do it that way instead we're going to
用这种方法。而是
create another new solid make it black
创建一个新的纯色，把它设为黑色。
click okay again let's scale it up just
再次点击确定。
a little bit parent it to the null go
稍微放大一点，把它父级设为空对象。
ahead and hide it for now and then draw
暂时把它隐藏起来。然后在
on this mask again make sure this black
这个遮罩上再次绘制。确保
Sol is selected a little shape around
选中这个黑色纯色。在
the outside of this tree and these
这棵树和
bushes down here now what we can do is
下面的灌木丛周围画一个小形状。现在我们可以选中
grab our copy we made earlier the one
之前创建的副本（
that's soloed and use this track map
独奏的那个），使用轨道映射，
pick Whip and select the black solid so
选择 Whip，然后选择黑色纯色。
that way if we click our black solid and
这样，如果我们点击黑色纯色，
hit F on the keyboard and start adding a
按下键盘上的 F 键并开始添加
feather it does react the way we want it
羽化效果，它就会按照我们想要的方式反应。
to so we can unsolo that and we pretty
取消这个操作后，我们就
much have a finished mat that's ready to
基本完成了一个可以
use all right now back in our main
使用的素材。好了，现在回到主
composition let's go ahead and start
合成中，我们开始
tweaking our buildings the first thing I
调整建筑物。首先，我
want to do is slide this over so that
想把这个物体往旁边移动一下，这样
way the explosion starts not at the
爆炸就不会从头开始，
beginning but instead roughly right when
而是在
the rocket would impact so I think
火箭撞击的瞬间开始。我觉得
around here looks pretty good scale this
这里看起来不错，缩小一下，
down maybe push it right about there and
也许可以把它推到这里。
you'll see obviously if we scrub
你会发现，如果我们
backwards the building just disappears
往后拖动，建筑物就会消失。
so in order to bring that to our start
为了把它放到开头，我们
let's rightclick go to time and choose
右键单击，选择“时间”，然后选择“
time remapping and we can just drag this
时间重映射”，就可以把它拖回开头了。
back out to the beginning I'm going to
我还要
rotate this also just a little bit to
稍微旋转一下，让它和
match our Skyline and now let's take
天际线匹配。现在我们来
care of the color cuz obviously this
处理颜色，因为很明显，它
the moment so let's add a levels
目前和场景不太搭。所以我们给建筑物添加一个色阶
adjustment to the building and one thing
调整。
I like to do is cycle between the red
我喜欢在调整色阶时，在红、
green and blue channels while adjusting
绿、蓝三个通道之间循环切换，同时相应地调整
the red green and blue on the levels
红、绿、蓝三个通道，使它们与
accordingly to match the sky so let's go
天空匹配。所以我们转到
to the red Channel go to the red channel
红色通道，在色阶中找到红色通道，
on the levels and let's start dragging
然后向上拖动
up this slider till it looks about how
这个滑块，直到…… 看起来差不多就是
we want it to go to the green do the
我们想要的效果了，绿色通道也
same and lastly the blue and now let's
一样，最后是蓝色通道。现在我们
switch it back over to RGB and it's
切换回 RGB 模式，效果相当不错。
looking pretty good if you notice one of
如果你发现某个
the colors is a little too dominant say
颜色太
you went a little heavy on the green and
突出，比如绿色加得有点多，导致
your building ends up looking like that
建筑看起来像那样，
you can just go to the specific channel
你可以直接找到那个
that you notice the color is too
颜色太
dominant and just play with that slider
突出的通道，调整滑块，
until you get it to match just a little
直到颜色更协调一些。
bit better now I also went ahead and
我还
downloaded this London City Skyline from
从 Production Crate 下载了伦敦城市天际线
production crate to fill out the
来填充
background of our scene so here in the
场景背景。在
project panel I already have that
项目面板中，我已经
imported let's drag it below our
导入了它，我们把它拖到
building explosion and then use the
建筑爆炸效果的下方，然后使用
track mat to pick our skym and don't
轨道材质选择天空背景，
forget to change it to Luma mat now next
别忘了把它改成亮度材质。接下来，我们用
whip scale it and place it where it
πwhip 工具把它父级化到空对象上，缩放并放置在合适的位置，
needs to be to roughly fill out the
大致填充
background and again we'll add that
背景。我们再次添加
levels adjustment and go through the
色阶调整，重复
same process and since this is a little
相同的步骤。由于这个场景距离较远，
further away I'm also going to add a
我还要添加一个
maybe around 2 pixels and now let's go
大约 2 像素的模糊效果。
ahead and bring in our other two
接下来，我们再添加另外两个
building explosion assets I have this
建筑爆炸素材。
one here which blows to the right and
这里有一个向右爆炸的，还有
also this one which blows to the left
一个向左爆炸的。
when I'm creating the shot what I'm
在创建镜头时，我
thinking about is the shock wave
考虑的是冲击波
exploding outward and affecting the
向外扩散，影响
buildings around it just to give it a
周围的建筑，这样比单纯的一座
were a single tall building and also
高楼更有视觉冲击力，也能让
help fill out the scene just that much
场景更加丰富。
more so let's drag in our next building
所以，我们把下一个建筑拖到
above the sky map painting but below our
天空贴图上方，主
main building explosion and we're going
建筑爆炸下方。操作步骤和
through the exact same process as before
之前一样：
pick whip the skym change it to Luma mat
选择天空贴图，将其转换为亮度材质；选择空对象，将
pick whip the null put it in place slide
其放置到位并
it over so that way the explosions are
拖动，使爆炸时间
timed up together and then adding our
同步；然后
levels adjustment and tweaking the color
调整色阶，并像
the same way as before now just as
之前一样微调颜色。和
before don't forget to enable time
之前一样，别忘了启用
remapping on this layer and drag it back
该图层的时间重映射，并将其拖回
to the beginning of the clip so that way
片段开头，以免
it doesn't just disappear now we can go
它消失。现在我们可以添加下一个
ahead and do our next building and I'm
建筑了。
just going to skip through this since
由于
all the steps are exactly the same all
所有步骤都相同，我就直接跳过这一步。好了，我们完成了
right and there we go we have our three
三个
main buildings in so let's go ahead and
主要建筑的爆炸。 建筑物已经就位，接下来我们
add in some additional detail including
添加一些细节，包括
a really cool shock wave and then we'll
一个非常酷炫的冲击波，然后
polish this up with some cool finishing
用一些炫酷的
effects and finally some color now for
特效来润色，最后上色。现在来说说
the main part of the shock wve I went
冲击波的主体部分。我
Shockwave 8 from production crate and I
从 Production Crate 下载了 World Breaker Shockwave 8 素材，并将
imported it into my After Effects
其导入到我的 After Effects
project so let's drag that out into our
项目中。现在我们把它拖到
main composition and let's put it above
主合成中，放在
all of our buildings now similar to our
所有建筑物的上方。和
buildings we are going to go ahead and
建筑物一样，我们将
use the skym so that way it appears
使用天空图层，这样它就会出现在
behind all of our foreground layers so
所有前景图层的后面。
change that to lumat after adding it and
添加之后，将其更改为亮度图层，
then also pick whip it to our null now
然后使用拾取鞭将其拾取到空对象。现在我们找到
let's go to the moment where the rocket
火箭
would hit the building right about here
击中建筑物的位置，将
and drag the beginning of the shock wave
冲击波的起始部分拖到
over to its brightest point and trim off
最亮的位置，然后修剪掉
the beginning now let's scale and
开头部分。现在我们调整它的位置，并将
blending mode to add now the shock wave
混合模式更改为“添加”。冲击波的
is expanding a little too slow but the
扩散速度有点慢，但
cool animated noise is already moving
炫酷的动画噪波已经移动得
pretty quick so instead of speeding up
很快了。所以，我们不加速
this clip let's add a scale animation by
这个片段，而是通过
hitting s on the keyboard and clicking
按键盘上的 S 键并点击
the stopwatch to create a key frame
秒表图标来添加一个缩放动画。 创建一个关键帧，我们
let's move forward in a timeline maybe
沿着时间线前进
20 30 frames and scale it all the way up
20到30帧，然后把它放大到
and almost out of frame maybe we'll have
几乎超出画面。也许我们可以让它
it Go just a little bit quicker and now
移动得更快一点。现在
that I'm looking at this I think it
我看着这个，觉得
would be cool if these side buildings
如果冲击波即将到达时，旁边的建筑物爆炸会很酷。
about to make impact so let's go ahead
所以我们抓住这
and grab both of those and slide them
两个建筑物，把它们
over just a couple frames that's looking
往旁边移动几帧。看起来很棒，只是
pretty cool except the shock wave is a
冲击波有点太
little bit too bright so let's hit t on
亮了。所以我们按一下键盘上的T键
the keyboard and let's lower the opacity
，降低一些不透明度，
some maybe around 20 or 30% and I'm also
大概20%到30%。我还想让它在
going to have this Fade Out as it hits
到达
the edges of the frame so maybe let's
画面边缘时淡出，所以我们在
create a key frame right in the middle
中间创建一个关键帧，
go forward a few frames until it's
前进几帧，直到它
barely visible anymore and then just
几乎看不见，然后把不
drop the opacity to zero production
透明度降到0。Production
crate also has these really cool aerial
Crate也有一些很酷的空中
explosions so I went ahead and
爆炸特效，所以我
downloaded ultimate explosion 5 aerial
下载了Ultimate Explosion 5 Aerial，
scene now now I've got that imported
现在我们要把它添加到场景中。我已经把它导入
into my After Effects project I'll drag
到我的After Effects项目中了。 我会把
that out above everything we've done so
它拖到我们目前为止所有操作的上方，
far and same as before let's use our Sky
和之前一样，我们使用天空
mat and our null now let's just slide
材质和空对象。现在我们把
this over so so the explosion lines up
它拖动过去，让爆炸效果对齐。
appropriately and I'm also going to cut
我还要
off just the first few frames of this
剪掉开头几帧，
put it into place and that's looking
把它放到合适的位置，看起来很酷。
pretty cool but obviously same as our
但显然，和
buildings before this is a little bit
之前的建筑一样，这里有点
too dark so let's add a levels
太暗了，所以我们来调整色阶，
process as we've done with the buildings
像之前调整建筑那样，在
changing between the red green and blue
红绿蓝通道之间切换。
channels that's looking pretty cool now
现在看起来很棒。
my first complaint from looking at this
我的第一个不满之处
is that the explosion definitely appears
是，爆炸效果看起来完全覆盖
to be sitting on top of the building and
在建筑顶部，
I want to be able to see some different
我希望能够看到一些
pieces of this debris and the building
碎片和建筑
itself poking through the explosion so
本身从爆炸中露出来。
in order to do that I'm going to grab
为了实现这一点，我要选中
our main building duplicate it with
主建筑，用
contrl d on the keyboard and bring it
键盘上的 Ctrl+D 复制它，然后把它拖回
back up to the top now let's grab our
顶部。现在我们用
pen tool and mask some of the areas that
钢笔工具遮罩一些朝
are coming towards us you can hit F on
我们飞来的区域（可以按键盘上的 F 键），
feather just a bit and this is already
稍微增加一下羽化效果。它已经
integrated pretty well however what I
融合得相当不错了，但是我
might do is hit M on the keyboard with
可能……
our top building layer selected and
选中顶层建筑图层，按下键盘上的 M 键，
create a key frame for the mask path and
为遮罩路径创建一个关键帧，
then go to the end of our composition
然后移动到合成的末尾，
and let's just adjust it so that way the
调整一下，让
smoke appears to be coming towards us
烟雾看起来像是朝我们飘来，
and engulfing more of the building as it
吞噬着更多
begins to Tumble now let's go ahead and
开始翻滚的建筑物。现在我们来
talk a little bit about the rocket that
谈谈
we see in the original shot for that
在短片原镜头中看到的火箭。
short I did end up simulating the smoke
我最终在
custom inside of Cinema 4D and attaching
Cinema 4D 中自定义模拟了烟雾，并将其附加到
from render crate on the production
Production
crate website there's a whole catalog of
Crate 网站上 Render Crate 的一个非常酷的导弹模型上。Production Crate 网站上有一个完整的
3D models and there's honestly some
3D 模型库，
really cool stuff in here so if you're
里面有很多非常棒的东西，所以如果你
into 3D make sure you go check out
喜欢 3D，一定要去看看。
what's here I utilized a bunch of these
我利用了很多这些
cool little weapons and sci-fi objects
很酷的小武器和科幻物件，
in order to Kit bash together the big
拼凑出了你在原短片中看到的那个
big transforming sci-fi weapon that you
大型变形科幻武器。
saw in that original Short now the smoke
现在，烟雾
Trail and the missile that were rendered
轨迹…… 在
out of Cinema 4D are able to be added to
Cinema 4D 中渲染的导弹可以
our shot the exact same way as the
像建筑物一样添加到镜头中：
buildings by dragging it in adding it to
拖入、添加到
the skym parenting it to the null and
天空背景、父级设置为空对象，
then scaling in positioning it into
然后缩放并定位
place if you don't have access to
到位。如果您无法模拟自
simulating something custom there are a
定义效果，Production Crate 网站上有一些
handful of good options on the
不错的选择，
production crate website particularly
特别是
these meteor across Sky trails that you
流星划过天空的轨迹，您
could track scale and position into
可以跟踪、缩放并定位到位，
place to simulate that rocket Trail
模拟火箭
going across the sky and just to sweeten
划过天空的轨迹。为了让
up that original rocket takeoff I did
火箭发射效果更逼真，我还
add an aerial smoke burst also able to
添加了空中烟雾效果，同样可以
be found on production crate but enough
在 Production Crate 上找到。不过，
about this smoke Trail for now let's go
关于烟雾轨迹就先说到这里，
we can do to make this shot a lot more
我们接下来讨论一些收尾步骤，让这个镜头更加
Dynamic and exciting so let's go ahead
动感和精彩。首先，
and grab our main composition from the
从
project panel and drag it down here to
项目面板中选择主合成，将其拖到这里，创建
bring it into a fresh composition which
一个新的合成。
I'll rightclick go to comp settings and
右键单击，选择“合成设置”，然后将其重
rename to finishing effects now here in
命名为“Finishing Effects”。现在，在
this PP is where we're going to add our
这个“Finishing Effects”中，我们将添加发光
glow our camera Shake as well as a few
效果、相机抖动以及一些
impact frames to make this have a little
冲击帧，让画面更有
bit more pop so let's go ahead and take
冲击力。
care of those impact frames first I'm
首先，处理一下冲击帧。我要把
going to drag my playhead to the moment
播放头拖到
that the rocket impacts right about here
火箭撞击的瞬间，大概在这里，
and hit control D to duplicate our
然后按 Ctrl+D 复制
footage and then we can also drag this
素材。之后，我们也可以把这个素材拖
in so it starts on this particular frame
进来，让它从这一帧开始播放。
uh or you can use the shortcut alt Open
或者，你也可以用快捷键 Alt+左
Bracket to do the very same thing next
括号 来做同样的事情。接下来，
I'm going to be using a plugin from the
我要用
production crate lege Suite called
Production Crate Legacy Suite 里的
easylow so so once you have that
EasyLow 插件。
installed you'll be able to find the
安装好之后，你可以在
easy glow in the search now in the
搜索栏里找到 EasyLow。现在，在
effects panel change the glow tint to
效果面板里，把发光色调改成
Something in the orange color range
橙色系的，
nothing too saturated maybe around here
不要太饱和，大概在这个范围内。
and then let's increase the tint
然后，我们来增加色调
strength next I'm going to hit control y
强度。接下来，我要按 Ctrl+Y
on the keyboard to create a new solid
创建一个新的纯色。同样，我们
again let's make something that's kind
创建一个
of light orange press okay we can hide
浅橙色的纯色。好的，我们可以
it for now and then let's grab our
暂时把它隐藏起来。然后，我们来选择
Circle mask tool if at the top you don't
圆形蒙版工具。如果你在顶部
see the circle you can access it by
看不到圆形蒙版工具，可以
clicking and holding on the rectangle
点击并按住矩形
mask tool to reveal all the options so
蒙版工具来显示所有选项。
select ellipse and then hold control and
选择椭圆，然后按住 Ctrl 键，
click and drag in the center of where
点击并拖动鼠标到中心。 找到
the explosion is and create a circle
爆炸点，画一个
probably about this big now we can turn
大概这么大的圆圈。现在我们可以
back on this orange solid and let's
重新选中这个橙色实心区域，然后
toggle these switches to change the
切换这些开关，把
blending mode to add now hit F to reveal
混合模式改成“添加”。现在按 F 键显示
the feather properties of your mask and
遮罩的羽化属性，然后大幅
let's increase this a whole bunch now
增加羽化值。和
same as our footage duplicate we want
我们的素材副本一样，我们希望
this orange solid to start on this
这个橙色实心区域从这一
particular frame so make sure it's
帧开始，所以确保
selected you can hit alt Open Bracket to
选中它。你可以按 Alt + 左方括号键把
bring it forward to where the playhead
它移动到播放头所在的位置。
is now I want this first impact frame to
现在我希望第一个冲击帧
be pretty much completely blown out I
几乎完全过曝，
don't want to see even close to as much
不想看到像现在这样多的
footage as we're seeing right here so
画面，所以
select your solid hit mm on the keyboard
选中这个实心区域，按键盘上的 M 键
to reveal the mask properties and let's
显示遮罩属性，然后把
expand this mask somewhere about there
遮罩扩展到大概这个位置，
feels good now create a key frame on
感觉不错。现在在这个帧上创建一个关键帧，
this frame for the mask expansion and
用于遮罩扩展，然后
let's move forward one frame and
向前移动一帧，把
decrease it probably about there now for
它缩小到大概这个位置。
the next couple impact frames I want it
接下来的几个冲击帧，我希望
to feel as if the camera's exposure has
看起来像是摄像机的曝光
automatically adjusted to compensate for
自动调整来补偿
this bright explosion so let's make make
这次明亮的爆炸，所以
sure this solid in this first footage
确保这个实心区域在第一个素材
duplicate and on this Frame so select
副本和这一帧上都选中，然后
them both and you can hit alt and
按 Alt + 左方括号键。
playhead now jump forward one more frame
现在，用括号将它们拉近播放头，再向前跳一帧，
and we're going to select our original
选中原始
footage hit controll D to create another
素材。按 Ctrl+D 创建另一个
copy and again all Open Bracket so it
副本，再次使用左括号，使其从当前
starts on this particular frame now with
帧开始。
your circle mask tool selected you can
选中圆形蒙版工具，
hold control click and drag in the
按住 Ctrl 键，点击并拖动鼠标在
center and create another Circle roughly
中心创建一个大小大致相同的圆形，
about that big around the explosion set
围绕爆炸区域。将
this particular mask to subtract and now
这个蒙版设置为减去。现在，
let's add a levels adjustment to this
我们给这个
top copy of the footage I'm going to
顶部的素材副本添加色阶调整。我将
start darking it in a ton until
逐渐降低亮度，直到除了
everything except for the sky is pretty
天空以外的所有部分
much completely crushed to Black now hit
几乎完全变成黑色。现在按
F on the keyboard and let's increase the
键盘上的 F 键，增加
feather so we don't have just a harsh
羽化值，这样就不会出现生硬的
circular Edge now next I'm going to
圆形边缘。接下来，我将
create a new adjustment layer which we
创建一个新的调整图层。
can do by coming up to layer new
可以通过选择“图层”&gt;“新建
adjustment layer or you can memorize the
调整图层”来创建，或者您可以记住
short cut contrl alt y to do the same
快捷键 Ctrl+Alt+Y 来执行相同的
thing again alt Open Bracket to bring
操作。再次使用 Alt+左括号，使
the adjustment layer to starts on this
调整图层从当前帧开始。
Frame and I'm going to add a curves
我将在
adjustment to this curves adjustment I'm
这个曲线调整图层中添加曲线调整。我
going to brighten it up some go to the
将提亮一些。转到
red Channel and increase that and now go
红色通道并增加其值。 现在
to the blue Channel and decrease that to
转到蓝色通道，降低它的数值，
create this warm glow now I'm also going
营造出这种温暖的光晕。接下来，我还要
to use another plug-in from The laforge
使用 Laforge Suite 中的另一个插件，
Suite called easy God Rays I'm going to
叫做 Easy God Rays。我会将
set the center to be where the explosion
中心点设置在爆炸的位置。
is and now we're going to go forward one
现在，我们再前进一
more frame select both of these new
帧，选中
layers we created and hit alt close
我们创建的两个新图层，然后按 Alt +
bracket to end them and now we've got
结束它们。现在我们有了
these four impact frames that create a a
四个冲击帧，它们能产生
really cool effect but as we come out of
非常酷炫的效果。但是，当爆炸结束后，
them it feels a little underwhelming
感觉有点不够强烈，爆炸
this explosion isn't standing out in the
在天空中不够突出。
sky as much as I'd like it to so let's
所以我们再
add some more glow now in order to make
添加一些光晕。为了
sure that just the explosion is glowing
确保只有爆炸在发光，
I'll show you a neat trick that I used
我将展示一个我在原始镜头中使用的巧妙技巧。我们
footage at the bottom one more time
再次复制底部素材，同样使用
again all Open Bracket so it starts on
开方括号，这样它就从
this Frame and next I'm going to add the
这一帧开始。接下来，我要添加
key light effect which is usually used
主光效果，它通常
for green and blue screens grab the
用于绿幕和蓝幕。选择
Color Picker and let's select one of
颜色选择器，从爆炸中选择一种橙色，将
change it from final result to combined
其从“最终结果”更改为“组合
mat and then we're going to throw on the
材质”。然后，我们将…… 启用
invert effect so that way the explosion
反转效果，这样爆炸就会变成
is white we can ignore all of these gray
白色。我们可以忽略所有
values that are showing up as those
显示的灰色值，因为添加完成
aren't going to be visible once we're
后它们将不可见。
finished adding this in now we can add
现在我们可以添加
another instance of production crates
另一个生产箱的
easy glow change the glow tint to
简易发光效果，将发光色调更改为
something orange and increase the tint
橙色，并增加色调
strength you're not going to see this do
强度。由于图像
a whole lot as the brightest parts of
中最亮的部分
the image are pretty small but as we
很小，所以你可能不会看到太多变化，但当我们
scrub forward you can really see what
向前拖动时，就能清楚地看到
this is doing however all of this
它的作用。然而，所有这些
glowing area is a little bit too sharp
发光区域都有些过于锐利，
so I am also going to throw on a fast
所以我还要添加一个快速
box blur so that way we can soften this
盒状模糊，这样我们就可以稍微柔化一下。
out just a bit next let's switch the
接下来，我们将
blending mode from normal to add and we
混合模式从“正常”切换到“添加”，我们
can continue tweaking these settings
可以继续调整这些设置，
maybe a little bit more blur maybe
也许可以增加一点模糊，或者稍微
decrease the intensity of the glow just
降低一点发光强度。
a hair and now let's go ahead and throw
现在，我们再添加一个
in another orange solid it should be the
橙色纯色，它的
same color as the previous one we
颜色应该与我们之前
created click okay let's draw a circular
创建的相同。单击“确定”。让我们在天空周围绘制一个圆形
mask around the sky this time set it to
蒙版，这次将其设置为“
screen hit F on the keyboard and let's
屏幕”。按键盘上的 F 键，然后
feather that out a whole bunch now
大幅羽化它。
obviously we don't want this solid to
显然，我们不希望这样。 为了让橙色纯色
composition so let's drag it in so it
图层在整个合成过程中保持效果，我们把它拖进来，让它
starts at the same time as our glow
和发光图层同时开始。
layer now that's looking pretty cool so
目前看起来很棒，但是
far except as the explosion goes on and
随着爆炸的进行和
the smoke takes over this is starting to
烟雾的扩散，效果开始
look just a little too intense so in
显得有点过强。
order to fix that what I'm going to do
为了解决这个问题，我要在
is go a few frames after the initial
初始爆炸开始后的几帧，为
frame for both the opacity on the orange
橙色
solid and on our building glow layer and
纯色图层和建筑发光图层的透明度都创建一个关键帧，然后
let's jump forward till later in the
跳到
explosion and let's drop these both down
爆炸的后期，把它们的透明度都降到
to zero that's looking pretty cool one
零。看起来很不错。在
more thing I'm going to do inside this
这个合成中，我还要做一件在
composition that I did in the original
原始
shot is add in a displacement map to
镜头中做过的事情：添加置换贴图，
further intensify this initial impact so
进一步增强初始冲击力。
to do that let's create a white solid
为此，我们创建一个白色纯色图层，
let's put it on top of everything else
把它放在所有其他图层之上。
I'm going to hide it for now so I can
现在我先把它隐藏起来，这样就能
see the explosion and let's draw a
看到爆炸效果。最后，我们再在
circular mask around it one last time
它周围画一个圆形遮罩。
now we can return on our solid layer
现在回到纯色图层，
select it and hit mm on the keyboard to
选中它，然后按键盘上的 M 键
bring up the mask expansion properties
打开遮罩扩展属性。
now let's go to when the explosion first
现在我们来看爆炸发生的时候。 首先，从
starts maybe a frame before our first
第一个冲击帧的前一帧开始，将
impact frame and drag the mask expansion
遮罩扩展值向
negative until the circle completely
负拖动，直到圆圈完全
disappears set a key frame now let's
消失。设置一个关键帧。现在我们
move forward till probably right around
继续向前，大概到
here when these secondary buildings are
这些次要建筑物
just about finished falling over and
即将倒塌的地方，然后
let's increase the mask expansion until
增加遮罩扩展值，直到
it completely fills the frame now next
它完全填满画面。接下来，
I'm going to select this mask and Hitt
我要选中这个遮罩，按 Ctrl+
control d to duplicate it and then let's
D 复制它。然后，我们将
set the second mask from add to subtract
第二个遮罩的模式从“添加”改为“减去”。
and also on the second mask I'm going to
同时，在第二个遮罩上，我要
grab these two key frames and slide them
抓住这两个关键帧，并将它们向外滑动
over two or three frames so if we play
两到三帧。这样，如果我们
this back you can see we've created this
回放这段视频，可以看到我们创建了一个不断
growing ring now this ring is going to
扩大的圆环。这个圆环将
drive our displacement so I don't want
驱动我们的置换效果，所以我不希望
it to be affecting the ground as much as
它对地面的影响像
it currently is however leaving it there
现在这样大，不过
just a little bit is fine so let's grab
稍微保留一点也是可以的。所以，我们选择
the mask pen tool and let's draw a mask
遮罩笔工具，在这个素材的
around the bottom foreground layers of
底部前景图层周围绘制一个遮罩，像
this footage just something like that
这样就
should do and let's change this to
可以了。然后，我们将模式改为“减去”。
subtract now if we select our solid and
现在，如果我们选中纯色图层并按
hit F we'll reveal all the feather
F 键，我们将显示所有
properties of our masks and we can start
遮罩的羽化属性，我们可以开始
softening this out maybe somewhere
柔化它，大概在……
around 200 on each should do the trick
每个都设为 200 应该就行了。
now last I want to add a solid composite
最后，我想给它添加一个纯色合成
effect to this and change it from white
效果，把它从白色变成
to black and then also throw on a
黑色，然后再加一个
turbulent displace let's increase the
湍流置换效果。我们来增大
size of this displacement but maybe
置换效果的大小，但稍微
decrease the amount just a hair if we
减小一下数值。如果我们把数值
set this from normal to screen and then
从“正常”设置为“屏幕”，然后
hit t on the keyboard we can decrease
按键盘上的 T 键，就可以降低不
the opacity so it's really low something
透明度，让它变得非常低，几乎
that's barely visible maybe around 10 to
看不见，大概 10% 到
15% and now that I'm looking at this I
15% 左右。现在我观察了一下，
can see it's growing just a little bit
发现它的增长速度
faster than our world breaker shock wave
比我们之前添加的“世界破坏者冲击波”要快一点，
that we added in earlier so I'm actually
所以我要按
going to hit U on the keyboard to reveal
键盘上的 U 键来显示
the key frames and drag these back key
关键帧，然后把这些关键
frames out just a hair so we can slow
帧稍微拖出来一点，让它慢
this down now lastly let's add a new
下来。最后，我们添加一个新的
adjustment layer remember that is contrl
调整图层，记住快捷键是 Ctrl+
alt y on the keyboard and we're going to
Alt+Y。我们要
add our final lege plugin which is
添加最后一个 Lege 插件，
called crates Distortion now this is
叫做 Crates Distortion。
going to look insane when you first add
刚添加的时候看起来会很夸张，
it but I'll show you how we can adjust
但我会教你如何调整
some of these settings to get it closer
一些设置来让它更自然。
to what we want first in the effects
首先，在效果
controls panel let's drop down
控制面板中，我们下拉“
displacement inputs and turn off blend
置换输入”，关闭“混合
iterations next let's go up to textures
迭代”。接下来，我们上拉“纹理”，将
and change the input to our white solid
输入更改为
that we created earlier with that
之前创建的带有
circular ring on it now don't forget to
圆形环的白色纯色。现在，别忘了将
change it from source to effects and
其从“源”更改为“效果和
masks so that way it takes into account
遮罩”，这样它就能同时考虑
both our solid composite and our
我们的纯色合成和
turbulent displace now drop down the
湍流置换。现在，下拉“
parameters and let's decrease the
参数”，将
strength from 35 which is default to
强度从默认值 35 降低到一个
something really low maybe like one and
非常低的值，比如 1。
it back it's adding this really cool
回放一下可以看到效果：它添加了一个非常酷的
Ripple that follows the ring that we
波纹，沿着我们创建的环延伸。
little bit too intense right now so
现在可能强度还是有点太强了，所以
maybe I'll set it to like8 and decrease
我把它设置为 8，并稍微降低
the X multiplier just a hair now let's
X 倍增器。现在，我们
zoom in just a little bit and start
稍微放大一点，开始
playing with these aberration sliders as
调整这些畸变滑块。向上拖动滑块，
we drag this up you can see we're
可以看到我们
starting to introduce some really nice
开始添加一些非常漂亮的
texture maybe just a little bit of blue
纹理，也许只是一点点蓝色，
not too much now I think we can call
不要太多。现在我觉得差不多可以了，当然，
obviously we don't want this to last for
我们不希望它持续
the entire duration of the clip so same
整个播放过程。 和
as before let's go to the very first
之前一样，我们来到
frame where the impact starts select our
冲击开始的第一帧，选择
adjustment layer and hit alt Open
调整图层，然后按 Alt + 左
Bracket so that way it's not rendering
括号，这样它就不会渲染
on the first portion of this composition
到合成的第一部分。
now we can go ahead and select all of
现在我们可以选择所有
these layers and hit control shift C to
这些图层，然后按 Ctrl+Shift+C 进行
pre-compose them and I'm going to call
预合成，我把
this comp impact frames now let's go
这个合成命名为“冲击帧”。
ahead and add in our camera shake for
接下来，我们添加镜头抖动效果。
that I'm going to be using Create camera
我将使用“创建镜头
Shake script which you can download and
抖动”脚本，你可以下载并将其放入
throw into your After Effects support
After Effects 的支持
files folder under scripts scripts UI
文件文件夹下的“脚本”→“脚本”→“UI
panels once that's there you'll be able
面板”文件夹中。找到后，你可以
to find it in the window drop down at
在底部的下拉菜单中找到它，它
the bottom with any other scripts you
和其他
have installed so select production
已安装的脚本放在一起。选择“
create camera shake and it's going to
创建镜头抖动”，它会
pop open this little handy dialogue for
弹出一个方便的小对话框。对于
this particular shot we're not going to
这个镜头，我们不
use Shake we're going to change it to
使用“抖动”模式，而是将其更改为“
the jolt mode now what jolt is going to
震动”模式。震动模式
do compared to shake is instead of
与抖动模式的区别在于，
it'll just add it for a few frames after
它不会将抖动添加到整个合成中，而是在播放头所在的位置之后的几帧内添加。
wherever the play head is once you hit
点击
this jolt button so let's go to the
震动按钮后，我们开始吧。 来到
start of our explosion right about here
爆炸的起始点附近，
and I'm going to increase the amplitude
我要增加振幅，
cuz I know I'm going to want this to be
因为我知道我想要
a very shaky shot and then maybe
一个非常晃动的镜头，然后
decrease the frequency so the shakes are
降低频率，这样晃动幅度
big but they're kind of slow and then we
大但速度慢。接下来我们
can hit jolt if you hit U on the
可以添加“抖动”效果。
keyboard with your layer selected you
选中图层后按键盘上的 U 键，
can see the key frames that it's added
可以看到添加的关键帧。说
and I honestly think that looks pretty
实话，我觉得效果
cool I might slow this down a little bit
很酷。我可能会稍微减慢一下速度，可以
which we could either do by deleting
通过删除
these key frames and lowering the
这些关键帧并降低
frequency or I can just click and drag
频率来实现，或者我可以点击并拖动
to select them all hold alt and pull the
选中所有关键帧，按住 Alt 键，然后拖动
back one out just to slow these all down
最后一个关键帧来减慢所有帧的速度。
and then we can also hit F9 so that way
然后我们还可以按 F9 键，这样
all of these are smooth that's looking
所有帧都会变得平滑。我觉得效果
pretty good to me so we can go ahead and
很不错，所以我们可以
close out of the script dialogue now the
关闭脚本对话框了。在
last thing we can do inside of this
这个合成中，我们最后可以做的
composition is add in just a little bit
就是添加一点
of color so it doesn't feel so flat so
颜色，让它看起来不那么单调。我们新建一个
let's throw on a new adjustment layer
调整图层，
remember Control Alt Y and then let's
记住是 Ctrl+Alt+Y，然后在
creative dropdown we can select through
创意下拉菜单中选择“亮度”颜色效果。
any number of these Luts I like this
我喜欢
Kodak film stock I think that looks
柯达胶片，我觉得这个LU​​T看起来
pretty cool now let's go to the basic
很酷。现在我们去基本
correction drop down and increase the
校正下拉菜单，增加
contrast maybe decrease the highlights
对比度，稍微降低一下高光。我们把
dragging the temperature to the right
色温向右拖动，让画面更暖一些，也许还
and maybe we can crush the blacks just a
可以稍微压暗一点暗部。
little bit now I'm going to throw on a
现在我要添加
curves adjustment and let's add a little
曲线调整，稍微增加一点
contrast S curve nothing too dramatic
对比度S曲线，不要太夸张。
and we can go to the blue and add a
我们也可以去蓝色区域也加一点
little S curve there as well and then
S曲线。然后
I'm also going to punch up the green
我还要稍微提升一下绿色，
just a little cuz I think that looks
因为我觉得这样看起来
kind of cool and there we go building
很酷。
exploded shot obviously there's a
好了，我们完成了爆炸图的构建。当然，还有一些
handful of things we could go back and
地方可以回头再
polish up but all the basic steps are
润色一下，但所有基本步骤都在
there I hope you guys enjoyed watching
这里了。希望你们喜欢这个视频，
let me know if you have any questions
如果有任何问题，请告诉我，我们下期再见！